Welcome to Business Central Launch
Edition 2026 Wave 2.
And welcome to this session about what's
new in approval process in expense
agent.
So, it will be an overview about some
features and we will go deep dive into
some of them.
What actually we have new about approval
process? First, we have AI-driven
approval policies. I will just make a
short overview about it because we will
have separate session about this process
completely so you can go deep dive
there.
Then, I want to emphasize enhanced and
hastened approval history and audit
trail. So, this is really important.
This is not only how you can approve,
when you can approve, but how deep you
can go to find all these changes in the
system. Then, we enable
interior approvers and some other
improvements as well. So, let's start
with the first.
First is, as I said, AI-driven approval
policies.
So, what is about? Admin can enable
AI-driven approval policies in setup.
So, this is only if you enable because
it can make some additional
spending of your AI
tokens. Then,
expense policies must be configured per
expense category. So, as you can see on
this screen, you can specify for each
category where you want to use, but what
is important? Expense policies usage and
AI usage will not be used for all your
categories. So, if you have expense
report with
I don't know, for example, 12 lines,
AI will you will be used only for these
lines where you have configured approval
policies. Because for some of them, they
are really clear, they are easy for
overview, so you do not need to use this
smart tool everywhere. So, only where
you really need, for example, for air
air flight tickets, this is important
when you can book business or economic
class, where you can upgrade. For then
for a hotel stay, when you can book
hotel with a five stars and so on. So,
this is how you can use and you can
configure only where you really need.
Uh this is uh additional recommended to
use itemization for all expenses to get
the best results because system can get
the best results from your receipt to
understand if you properly used uh
money from your company only if you have
uh
look into all details from this receipt.
And this is on the end it helped to
approvers. So, it will work
automatically if you enable for your
approvers. So, approvers will see if
some of expenses if flagged or not
before final approval. It will not block
approvers. So, you can even uh approve
even if this uh expense is flagged, but
this is something what will help
approvers to make smarter decision.
>> [clears throat]
>> But, it can be also used by submitters
as employees. So, I can run manually. It
will not be done automatically, but I
can run manually to see in advance if my
expense is compliance or not.
So, let's switch to another topic. And
here's approval history and audit trail.
So, now I will go directly to demo to
show what we have.
Okay, now I am in my expense agent uh
web app. And if I look into my history,
now you can see I have more tabs here.
So, I have draft, submitted, approved,
history. So, this is what all employees
have. But, if you are in the same time
approver, you will see for my approval
and approve history. This is only uh
what approvers can see. But, now this is
not a topic. I want to look as a on my
side as a submitter what I have here.
So, in my history, I can see this one
expense and I can go into details. When
I look into details, I can see here that
I created this September 16th 8:49 and
submitted the same time. This is still
not approved. So, I can see all the all
changes what happened in the meantime.
But, if I go deeper, I will go this one.
And then you can see much more
information. What happened here?
September 11, created by Alexander.
12 minutes later, this is submitted for
approval.
And then it was rejected
5 days after that because approver, in
this case, I am the same a person who
rejected, but this is a place where you
can see your approval name and you will
get justification or justification ex-
explanation why this is rejected. So,
please confirm flight ticket class.
So, this is a reason. So, you have all
this information added. And then when I
resubmitted, I can see my message from
my
approver again and the justification in
the system. So, you can see all these
changes even if I made some changes in
amounts, reimbursement amount,
everything will be tracked here. And on
the end you will see that this is
approved
1 minute later after I resubmitted the
last time. So, you can see all these
changes here.
And
on the end, you can see here different
color
and different
letters. Why? Because now this is
posted.
Uh what is the difference in general?
Here
before posted, this is everything what
was done in a web app in Expense Agent
directly, but now you know
um
you must be Business Central user to be
able to post. And this is why we have
this is Business Central uh username and
this is different color. So, this is
posted by Business Central user and
okay, again amounts, when it's posted
and all these details. So, this is what
we have in a web app. But now, let's
look what we have in a Business Central
app.
So, I want to show what I have here in a
Business Central. So, if I take one of
my expenses here, for example, this one.
If I go inside, you will see
here that I history
here as well. So, this is the same
history regardless if you're in a busy
central on a web app. What is different?
You in web app it is exposed to all
regardless if you're busy central or
user or not. So, this is exposed there.
You You just need to be busy central
busy You just need to be expense user to
see it. But, if you're in the same time
busy central user or your accountant
whoever with a rights to open
app in a busy central, you can see the
same history here. So, you can see that
this is created
exactly time and date other details,
when it is submitted, and the same thing
will appear if this is a posted. If I
turn to another expense report
there is nothing here because it was not
submitted.
So, you can see
that history can be changed. Now, this
is again created, submitted. So, you can
see this history either expense report
or posted expense report.
Now, I want to show what will come
in next minor.
And this news is important in some more
complex scenario of approvals. And what
is about? This is about enable interim
approvers. So, from next minor from
November in some situations, you need
more approvers. So, how to resolve this?
And why we need more approvers? Because
you have final approval as your manager.
But, sometimes someone need to check
your expense report against compliance
reasons if this is everything is a
legal. So, if there is no any problem
about expense report, so you can use for
example accountant or you can use any
other person who needs to review before
final approval. So, you can add your
interim approver in expense report and
interim approver must approve before
final approver. So, this is what we will
have from next version. And in the
future, we have a plan to add more
options for approval in the approval
process.
But, just stay tuned and you will see
what we're coming about in the
approvals.
Other approvals, so now I I just
mentioned some other approvals again uh
coming from uh November 29.1.
Better messaging during approval
process.
So, you will see completely different
messages when you reject uh when you
approve, so we have different icons,
different colors, so you can you can
work much easier with your or workflow
with approvals.
And then
uh
what else? This is again based on your
feedback, you will have approval limits.
So, in this moment, we have approver or
not. So, if you are approver, you can
approve everything. But, from uh
November
uh minor, you will be able to set up
approver with a uh with a maximum
approval amount, for example, $2,000,
and you can set up unlimited. So, you
will have two levels, one will be uh
have specific amount, another uh
unlimited. You can specify only
unlimited, so it will behave the same
way as we have right now, but if you
have different levels, you can you can
make this way. But, what is important,
you can have multi you cannot have
multiple levels, so you cannot have one
uh for 1,000, 2,000, 5,000, so you will
have one uh with a specific amount, and
you need to have who is next in a charge
with unlimited. So, this is what we will
have with approval limits.
And um additionally one, we will have
alternate and delegated approvers. So,
this is important, and this is again
based on feedback, and we will have two
options.
First option is ad hoc alternate
approver. What does it mean?
Um I'm from this moment, if I'm a sick
leave and I approver, I can easily
delegate all expense reports on my name
sent to me to approve to some of my
colleagues who can approve. What is
important, I can delegate and I can use
alternate approvers only if they are set
up as approvers, so if they are not
approvers, they cannot be uh used for
approving as delegated. So, I can send
to my colleague and all expense reports
will be redirected from me to another
colleague. So, this is ad hoc for
already sent
expense report for approving. But, for
plan alternate approvers, this is
different. So, I'm planning to go
vacation in 2 weeks and I will be home 1
month outside of office. So, I can make
plan alternate approver from
for example, from October 1st until the
end of October, I will choose who will
approve instead of me. So, system will
automatically redirect
all expense reports to this new
alternate approver. So, this is what how
we will have about alternate and
delegated approvers from November.
And I just wanted to mention travel
request approval. So, this is new. We
have separate session about travel
request, so you can go there and see
what is about, but this is new option we
are adding as well about approvals.
So, that's it about approvals, but stay
tuned because in next wave, we will
deliver more and more improvements in
approvals.
So, thank you for watching this video.